Guide to the Stanford University, Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics, records
1962-2001
SC0634
Stanford University. Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics.
40 Linear feet
Correspondence, grant files, research files, patents, concert programs, articles, clippings, photographs, and other records. Collection also includes electronic media, video and audiotapes, architectural drawings, radio-baton, and a computer. People represented in these records include John Chowning, John R. Pierce, Max V. Mathews, and John M. Grey; there are files pertaining to the Institut de Recherche et de Coordination Acoustique/Musique (1975-1990) and to the Catgut Acoustical Society (1991-1994).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 2001. Accession ARCH.2013-082 gift of Ed Feigenbaum, 2013.
Information about Access
Electronic media and audio-visual materials currently not available for use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford University Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics (CCRMA) is a multi-disciplinary facility where composers and researchers work together using computer-based technology both as an artistic medium and as a research tool. Areas of ongoing interest at CCRMA include: composition, applications hardware, applications software, synthesis techniques and algorithms, physical modeling, real-time controllers, signal processing, digital recording and editing, psychoacoustics and musical acoustics, music manuscripting by computer, and real-time applications.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, grant files, research files, patents, concert programs, articles, clippings, photographs, and other records. Collection also includes electronic media, video and audiotapes, architectural drawings, radio-baton, and a computer. People represented in these records include John Chowning, John R. Pierce, Max V. Mathews, and John M. Grey; there are files pertaining to the Institut de Recherche et de Coordination Acoustique/Musique (1975-1990) and to the Catgut Acoustical Society (1991-1994).
Access Terms
Catgut Acoustical Society.; Chowning, John M.; Grey, John M.; Institut de recherche et de coordination acoustique/musique.; Mathews, Max V.; Pierce, John R. (John Robinson), 1910-2002; Stanford University. Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics.; Computer music.; Music--Acoustics and physics.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - NEA Proposals Computer Music Facility, 1974
    - 1974 NEA Prposals Computer Music Facility (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - NEA Grant for Center, 1974-1975
    - Grants for Music Center NEA & NSF 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Composers Win Grant" Palo Alto Times March 28, 1974 Chowning/ Rush (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - NEA Equipment/ facility support, 1979-1983
    - NEA 92-3134-538 Facility Support 6-1-79-6-1-80 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - NEA Facilities Support Proposal submitted 11/26/79 to begin 6/1/80 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - NEA Revised Budget 6-1-80 to 5-30-81 $ 12315 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - NEA Facility Support 6-1-81 to 6-1-82 submitted 9-1-80 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chowning proposal 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Revised budgets NEA 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - NEA A-81-215723 Equipment June 1982-May 1983 original & revised (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - NEA Pub-CCRMA news Oct-Nov 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - NEA Recording CCRMA composers, 1981-1987
    - NEA Recording program submitted Oct 19. 1983 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - NEA Recording program 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Recording project #1 McNabb-Aich Street 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - NEA- Centers Grants, 1983-1985
    - NEA- Center Grants 1983-1984, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - NEA application June 1983-1984 original (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - NEA application 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - NEA- McNabb "Robot Ballet", 1986
    - Computer Robot Ballet (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - NEA Facility Renovation Grant, 1984-1987
    - NEA advancement grant facility renovation 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NEA Equipment Grants, 1986-1988
    - NEA Centers application 1986-1987 for mixing console (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - NEA Centers 1987-1988 Sampson Box Maintenance (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - NEA Wynton Marsalis Project
    - NEA Special projects March 1986-1989 Final outcomes of Wynton Marsalis project (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1987 NEA special projects Wynton Marsalis (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Wynton Marsalis 1987 project Expense projection (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - NEA Synthesizer Maintenance Grant, 1988-1989
    - NEA "Centers" 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - NEA Centers for New Music Resource, 1985-1988
    - NEA 1985-1986 Centers (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - NEA Centers for New Music Resources due postmark September 30 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - NEA (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - NEA Recordings Chowning, 1987-1988
    - Chowning Recording Program (third recording porject funded) due postmark Sept. 30 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - NEA recordings 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - NEA Center for New Music Resources proposal and budgets, 1989
    - NEA Center for New Music Resources 1989 proposal and budgets 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - NEA-McNabb opera, 1990
    - McNabb NEA Inter-Arts 1/1990 "Galilea" an image opera (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Untitled
    - NEA Final Reports and matching (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - NEA Centers 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - NEA Sponsor/CCRMA recordings to Library of Congress, 1994
    - NEA to Library of Congress-Recording Projects (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Summaries of NEA grants
    - Summaries of NEA grants (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Rockefeller proposals, grant, 1980s
    - Rockefeller 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller proposal 1982 and supporting materials (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Rockefeller 1st Poposal, letter 1979-1980 (Boulez letter) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Rockefeller Correspondence 1981-1983 (and grant letter) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Rockefeller Applications, letters 1983-1987 begin date January 1986 Schoba, Malouf and Halstrom (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Rockefeller Composers reject letters-proposal 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Rockefeller Artist-in-Residence 9/17/87 Proposal for 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rockefeller/Argentina Exchange, 1990s
    - Rockefeller-south America Consortium (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller Report 1993-1994, 1995, 1996- end spring 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Rockefeller Argentina exchange etc. 4th year 10-1-1993 to 9-30-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Argentina- Equipment LIPM Fr. Kropfl 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Rockefeller Exchange LIPM Stanford and UCSD 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Rockefeller Third year cooperative composers program LIPM,UCSD, Stanford (Argentina) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Argentina Exchange Rockefeller
    - Argentina Exchange Rochefeller (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Rockefeller 1994-1995-1996 Participant Summaries (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Rockefeller: Bio and Notes (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Rockefeller Exchange Program Documents: Permissions and Photos (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Argentina Exchange Admin. Documents (Rockefeller)
    - Argentina exchange - LIPM Rockefeller grant [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Argentina exchange - LIPM Rockefeller grant [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - SDF grants, 1982
    - System Development Foundation 1982 Grant [letters, proposal forms, expenses] (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - SDF General Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - SDF Budgets 5 year support (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - SDF- COMITS, 1982-1984
    - SDF- Research project definition 1982-1983 meetings, general plans [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - SDF- Research project definition 1982-1983 meetings, general plans [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - SDF- Specific Proposals for different systems [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - SDF- Specific Proposals for different systems [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - SDF 1982-3-Issues, discussions, memos [1of 3] (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - SDF 1982-3-Issues, discussions, memos [2 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - SDF 1982-3-Issues, discussions, memos [3 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - SDF Annual reports, 1982-88
    - SDF Annual Reports 6/30/1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - SDF Annual Reports 6/30/1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - SDF Annual Reports 6/30/1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - SDF CD Project, 1988
    - SDF Benchmark Recording CD Project 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - SDF Benchmark Symposium and Book on Computer Music 1985-1988
    - SDF Benchmark Symposium and Book on Computer Music 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - SDF Progress Reports and Financial Reports 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - SDF Symposium and Book (letters) 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Benchmark Budgets (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - SDF Progress Report - Expense Reports - letters - unspent money 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - DARPA--Pierce and Jos proposal, 1985
    - DARPA 1985 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - DARPA Proposal - Resources (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - DARPA-Mont-Reynaud, 1990
    - DARPA-Mont-Reynaud, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Auditory Organization in Humans and Machines--BMR/Duda--San Jose State (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - DARPA-Mont-Reynaud, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - California Arts Council (CAC)
    - CAC Agreements - Artistic and Administrative Development Award 1982-83 funded (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - CAC Proposal 1983 (and supporting materials, new article reprints, etc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - California Arts Council (CAC) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - NSF and NEA Grant Letters, 1975-1976
    - NSF and NEA Grant Letters 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - NSF Grant News Articles, 1975
    - Article: $400,000 for computer music research center, NSF and NEA, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NSF- Chowning/Smith "Perceptual Modeling" proposal and budget, 1974-1975
    - NSF- Chowning/Smith 1974-1975: Perceptual Modeling" proposal and budget (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Timbre Perception
    - Timbre Perception for Complex Time- Variant Tones, NSF, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Timbre Perception for Complex Time- Variant Tones, NSF, 1975- Draft (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - National Institue of Health (NIH) Proposal Withdrawn 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - GREY Instrumental Timbre (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - NSF - L. Smith and J. Chowning, Computer Simulation of Music, budgets, 3/15/1976- 2/28/1978+6 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - NSF - Computer Music - John Chowning Experiements in Timbre Perception (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Timbre Perception" final reports 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NSF- "Timbre" research proposals, budgets, letters, 1977-1980
    - "Timbre" 406 - Amendment 02 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - NSF Grant - 1977 Sept. #7722305, Behavioral and Neural Sciences (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Timbre" renewal submitted January 1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Timbre" 406 - Amendment 01 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - NSF 1980 Proposal progress report and expense adjustments (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - NSF - JMG 9/1/1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - NSF--L. Smith, J. Chowning, Computer Simulation of Musical Instrument Tones, 1975
    - Computer Simulation of Musical Instrument Tones in Reverberant Spaces (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Computer Simulation of Musical Instrument Tones in Reverberant Spaces (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - NSF Interactive Graphical Environments Grant Approval, 1977-1979
    - NF June 1977 extra master (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - NSF - John Chowning, An Interactive Graphical Environment for Musical, Acoustical, and Psychoacoustical Research (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Interactive 405 Renewal (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - NSF--Chowning, Grey, Moore, Moorer, and Rush, 1977
    - An Interactive Graphical Environment for Musical, Acoustical, and Psychoacoustical Research (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NSF--John Chowning An Interactive Graphical Environment, Etc.
    - NSF Proposal June 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - NSF Architecture--not funded, 1979 Nov 20
    - NSF Architecture - not funded - 11/20/1979 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - NSF Architecture - not funded - 11/20/1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - NSF Sound Localization, 1979 Nov 20
    - International Telephone/Telegraph (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - NSF Sound Localization 11/20/1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - NSF--"Auditory Distance" 2 Proposals, 1979-1981
    - Auditory Distance 1978-1979 Correspondence-request for use of subjects (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Auditory Distance 1980-1981 Original (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Auditory Distance Reviews-Evaluations of Proposal-original 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Auditory Distance NSF BNS-7924645 Award Letter (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - NSF Auditory Distance, 1979-1980
    - Auditory Distance Perception Under Natural Sounding Conditions, CCRMA, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Auditory Distance Perception Under Natural Sounding Conditions, CCRMA, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Auditory Distance Perception Under Natural Sounding Conditions, CCRMA, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Intelligent Systems" NSF Joint SCI/CCRMA proposal, 1980
    - SCI Meeting January 1981 -notes, Systems Control Inc. (SCI) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Intelligent Systems" NSF Joint SCI/CCRMA 1980 proposal [1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Intelligent Systems" NSF Joint SCI/CCRMA 1980 proposal [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Intelligent Systems for Musical Analysis"
    - "Intelligent Systems for Musical Analysis" (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - NSF Summary of Award, 1981
    - NSF Summary of Awards 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NSF "Intelligent Systems", 1982-1984
    - NSF Proposal, "Intelligent Systems" 9/1/1982 - 3 years (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - NSF Final Report, "Inteligent Systems" 1980- 1982 MCS 80- 12476 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Revised budgets and continuation 7/1984 MCS 82-14350 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NSF, 1985
    - NSF 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - NSF "Intelligent Analysis of Composite Acoustic Signals" submitted May 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - NSF "Intelligent Analysis of Composite Acoustic Signals" Revised budget March 1, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Acoustics Proposal, 1985, Borish, not funded (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - NSF- Pierce and Schubert, 1987
    - Pierce, Schubert Proposal NSF submitted 7/15/1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Max Matthews Research Proposals NSF/NSA, 1987
    - Speech Synthesis proposal- NSA [National Security Agency] (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Max Matthews NSF Research Proposals (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - NSF Proposals (letters), 1987-1988
    - Matthews, Pierce, NSF submitted 8/1/1987 [1 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Matthews, Pierce, NSF submitted 8/1/1987 [2 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Matthews, Pierce, NSF submitted 8/1/1987 [3 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - NSF Proposals, 1988-1989
    - STC-Center for Integrated Research in Communication Acoustics [1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - STC-Center for Integrated Research in Communication Acoustics [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - The Acquisition of Musical Percepts with a new Scale (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Intelligent Analysis of Composite Acoustic Signals (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Articulation-Based Speech Recognition Research (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - NSF-JOS- Reject "Vocal Modeling", 1994
    - JOS NSF Proposal 3/7/1994 Visual and Acoustic Modeling (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - IRI-8613574-Final Report-Progress report and budget for 2nd year renewal (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - NSF/JOS "Discrete-Time Simulation", 1996-2000
    - NSF Proposal-June 1996-JOS/Berner-Tavel to France only-until 2000 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - NSF, 1993-1996
    - NSF J. Smith "Vocal Tract…" revised proposal-additional costs 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Funding Proposals
    - Hewlett-Packard Proposal October 1986 Request for Equipment (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Chafe proposal to Univ. Techn. Transfer, Inc. Chafe Proposal Sept. 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - CLARITY/CCRMA Project Mr. Greg Framer 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Perry Cook Acoustical Society Proposal for Post-Doc 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Donations-Private
    - Hewlett Packard 1986 donation, Dynamic Signal Analyzer and Computer, etc. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hewlett Packard Gift Ext. Non-Violatile memory 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Motorola Donation 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - PCB Piezotronics, Ins. Donation 1994- Accelerometer and Hammer (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1997 Hewkett Packard Donation via Walter Hewlett computer, monitors, and accessories (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fundraising, 1970s
    - Department Fund Sources- 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Budget Projections 1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Funding Letters Separation from AI and CS, 1979-1980
    - Mellon Foundation no support 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Letters-1979-1980 Seeking sunding CCRMA separation from AI (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Private donors
    - Gordon Getty (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Doreen Townshend 1979-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Funding History, 1970s, 1980s
    - CCRMA Grants List 1970s and 1980s (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Move to Knoll
    - Knoll-Map of Rooms (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Spanish Colonial Revival "The Knoll" from Stanford Community Report Fall/Winter 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Fundraising Move to Knoll JC's file 1980s (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Funding Building and Equipment NEA, Doreen Townshend, Stanford University (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - CCRMA-Knoll Dedication April 17, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Move to Knoll-Memos, etc.
    - Naming the Knoll (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Budgets/Form II's (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Space Requirements/Scope of Project (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Knoll Refurbishing
    - Knoll Plans 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Funding for move to Knoll 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Knoll Refurbishing-memos 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Knoll Facility completion-expenses 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Knoll-BOT presentation 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Knoll Materials paint, carpet, etc. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Knoll Problems, 1980s
    - Knoll Problems 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Knoll Scheduling and Noise 1986 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 1988-1989 Structural Evaluation of the Knoll (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Knoll Garage and CCRMA Space Requirements (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Knoll Security and Maintenance 1986-1988 (O and M) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Knoll Drains 1987 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Knoll Post-Quake Retrofitting
    - Earthquake Invoices (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Knoll 3rd floor (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Knoll Misc. Problems, 1990s
    - Knoll Ventilation and Heat Problems (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Knoll Maintenance 1994 misc. problems (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Trailer Alarm 1994 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Knoll Cracks 1994 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Asbestos Notification 1994 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Knoll Misc. Projects
    - Classroom Annex Listening Space 10/1989 just before Earthquake (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Midi Studies Upgrades 1990 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Knoll Dorms 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Trailers Work 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - 1994 Bid Shop Contractor (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Room 108 Studio Project 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Equipment--major
    - Purchase of Foonly and Smson Vos 1979 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Equipment Theft 1984 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Systems Concepts Samson Box Maintenance 76-8/88 Folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Historical Samson Box Diagram (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Equipment List September 1987 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - 1989 CCRMA Equipment theft newsclip--$45,000 computers stolen (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - 1990 NEXT machine-memos, news articles (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Garage sale-Equipment Lists 1991 ad 1992 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Equipment Garage Sale April 4, 1992 Michael Goldbach coor. (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Samson Box to Paris-1993-List of early Samson Box pieces of J. Berger and B. Schoffstaedt (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Equipment--Minor
    - Different models of copiers on loan at CCRMA-summer of 1989 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Equipment-minor [1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Equipment-minor [2 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Misc. Hardware and Software
    - Macsyma Primer MIT 1975 (Mathlab Group)(Comp. Prog. In LISP) (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Chadabe, J and Meyers, R. Intro to "The Play Program" 1978 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Quadraphonic headphones (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - CCRMA Equipment, Digital Audio Report (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Dartmouth Alumni Magazine - The Well-Tempered Synclavier, Brochure "Synthia" 1982 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - alphaSyntauri digital synthesizer in Studio Sound 9/83 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Computers and Music- 1985 about products (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - ITG Journal-Dec. 1989 Report on Conferencce; Santa Barbara (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - "Jaminator" 5/31/1990 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Keyboard Magazine 11/1991 Thomas Dougherty (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - CCRMA Search for Record (CD) Producer, 1980s
    - Recording Proposals DAJ-July 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Recording Project 1985-1988 (CCRMA rejects OWL- goes with WERGO) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - CRI: Letter (rejects CCRMA proposals) 1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Historical CD
    - Historical CD (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Historical CD (Wergo Offer) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - IDEAMA miscellaneous docs.
    - Mathews-diagram fo Equipment Costs and misc. docs. 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - IDEAMA partners contract 1991 CCRMA/ZKM (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Target Collection Lists of Works (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mellon/IDEAMA funding
    - Mellon-Achive Proposal, misc. docs., letters; funded 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mellon/NEA/NEA Matching (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Random stuff-achival proposal (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Archive Project-notes (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - ZKM Equipment docs, 1991-1993
    - Equipment ZKM Financial reports, lists (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Karlsruke equipment-shipping docs 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - NEA-IDEAMA, 1992-1994
    - NEA IDEAMA -Funded 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - NEH IDEAMA Grant (Mathews), 1993-1994
    - NEW proposal 1991 IDEAMA (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - WERGO CD project
    - 1987-1999 Schallplatten GmbH JC contract/Dinosaur Music correspondence 1987-1999 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - WERGO CD series 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - WERGO series CD orders 1990-1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 1992 MAX CD- Radio-baton pieces Vol. 15 of WERGO series -memos (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - WERGO CD project mailing (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Complimentary Set-Distribution (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - CD- WERGO Distribution (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Computer Music Currents- 1990- Review list and copies (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - WERGO CD series Computer Music Currents-Distribution (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - CD Series (WERGO)-budgets (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - WERGO CD Series Letters, Agreements
    - Schott-Wergo CD's Agreement Letters 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - CD Project 1988 Pending Permission letters (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - WERGO CD Series memo's agreements, letters, content of series
    - WERGO-computer music currents (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - WERGO CD Series Selected and Rejected Pieces-Letters
    - selected pieces-letters (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - reject letters (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - WERGO Selection letters
    - Albright, William, "Sphaera" (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - ARFIB, Daniel, "Le soufflé du doux" CD II (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - BARRIERE, Jean-Babtiste, "Chieode I" CD IV (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - BAYLE, Francois, "Le Sommeil d'Euclide" CD III (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - BENNETT, Gerald, "Kyotaku" CD IX (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - BODIN, Lars-Gunnar, "Anima" CD VII (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - BOESCH, Rainer, "Clavirissima" CD VIII (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - CHAFE, Chris, "Solera" CD VI (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - DAVIDOVSKY, Mario, "Synchronisms #9" CD II (Box 6, Folder 40)